Hell, any of them could have done it.
Knives Out is a comedy, crime, mystery film directed by Rian Johnson.
When renowned crime novelist Harlan Thrombey is found dead at his estate just after his 85th birthday, the
inquisitive and debonair Detective Benoit Blanc is mysteriously enlisted to investigate.
From Harlan's dysfunctional family to his devoted staff, Blanc sifts through a web of red
herrings and self-serving lies to uncover the truth behind Harlan's untimely death.
Benoit Blanc, played by Daniel Craig.
Ransom Drysdale, played by Chris Evans.
Marta Cabrera, played by Ana de Armas.
Linda Drysdale, played by Jamie Lee Curtis.
Walt Thrombey, played by Michael Shannon.
Richard Drysdale, played by Don Johnson.
Knives Out is a 2019 American mystery film written and directed by Rian Johnson.
The film's eleven-actor ensemble cast is led by Daniel Craig as Benoit Blanc, a famed private detective
who is summoned to investigate the death of a bestselling author (Christopher Plummer).
Police think his death is a suicide but Blanc suspects foul play
and investigates to ascertain the true cause of it.
Johnson produced Knives Out with his longtime collaborator Ram Bergman.
Funding came from MRC and tax subsidies from the Massachusetts state government.
Johnson conceived Knives Out in the mid-2000s.
Wanting to create work reminiscent of whodunit films of the mid-twentieth century, the director
was influenced by his interest in movie adaptations of Agatha Christie's stories.
Development of Knives Out continued after Johnson finished
filming Star Wars: The Last Jedi (2017).
He wrote the screenplay in six to seven months.
Principal photography on Knives Out began in October 2018 on a
$40 million budget and ended that December.
Location filming took place in suburban Boston.
Nathan Johnson composed the film's classical score, which was
inspired by his and Rian's favorite symphonic movie scores.
Knives Out has been read as a work that investigates class warfare, wealth
inequality, immigration, and race in contemporary American society.
Knives Out premiered at the 44th Toronto International Film Festival on September 7,
2019, and was distributed by Lionsgate to American theaters on November 27.
The film was a critical and commercial success; the National Board of Review and the American Film
Institute chose it as one of the year's top films, and it grossed $312 million.
Knives Out received highly positive reviews from critics, who praised the plot and
actors but occasionally criticized aspects of the writing and performances.
It was nominated for multiple awards, including three Golden Globes, a British
Academy Film Award, and an Academy Award for Best Original Screenplay.
Knives Out is the first entry of a series of films that also
includes Glass Onion (2022) and Wake Up Dead Man (2025).
The film explores themes of immigrant, detective,
massachusetts, investigation, big family.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and mind_bending.